Guide to the Student Liberation Action Movement (SLAM!) Oral Histories TAM.799
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Student Liberation Action Movement (SLAM!) Oral Histories
2012-2014
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Okechukwu, Amaka
TAM.799
2.77 Gigabytes in 44 computer files
The Student Liberation Action Movement (SLAM!) was a citywide radical student activist group, based at Hunter College (City University of New York) and formed in 1996 out of the dissolution of the CUNY Coalition in 1995. SLAM!'s main organizing concern was to stop the budget cuts and tuition increases at CUNY. The group also organized around welfare, Ethnic Studies, police on campus, incarceration, war, and other social justice movements. This collection consists of oral history interviews in electronic format with SLAM! activists conducted between 2012-2014 by Dr. Amaka Okechukwu, an interdisciplinary scholar, author, oral historian, and Assistant Professor in the Department of Sociology and Anthropology at George Mason University, as a part of Dr. Okechukwu's dissertation research which she completed in the Department of Sociology at NYU. The collection comprises 15 interviews with SLAM! members and collaborators, consisting of audio recordings in mp3 format and transcripts. As a part of her research process, Dr. Okechukwu's oral history work on this project was additionally reviewed and approved by NYU's Institutional Review Board (IRB). At least one interview, that of Suzy Subways, has been corrected. Topically, the interviews cover subjects such as the fight to save open admissions at CUNY; the origins, life-course, and decline of SLAM; young people of color organizations in New York City in the 1990s and 2000s; radical organizing on the Left in New York City in the 1990s and 2000s; and the individual biographies of each activist. Narrators in this collection include Kazembe Balagun, Jesse Ehrensaft-Hawley, Kamau Franklin, Camillo Gaston-Greenberg, Orlando Green, Neha Guatam, Chris Gunderson, Sabrine Hammad, Rachel LaForest, Mariano Munoz, Lenina Nadal, Irene Neofotistos, Brad Sigal, suzy subways, and Hank Williams.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of oral history interviews in electronic format focused on the Student Liberation Action Movement (SLAM!) conducted between 2012-2014 by Dr. Amaka Okechukwu, an interdisciplinary scholar, author, oral historian, and Assistant Professor in the Department of Sociology and Anthropology at George Mason University, as a part of Dr. Okechukwu's dissertation research which she completed in the Department of Sociology at NYU. The collection comprises 15 interviews with SLAM members and collaborators, consisting of audio recordings in mp3 format and transcripts. As a part of her research process, Dr. Okechukwu's oral history work on this project was additionally reviewed and approved by NYU's Institutional Review Board (IRB). At least one interview, that of suzy subways, has been corrected. Topically, the interviews cover subjects such as the fight to save open admissions at CUNY; the origins, life-course, and decline of SLAM; young people of color organizations in New York City in the 1990s and 2000s; radical organizing on the Left in New York City in the 1990s and 2000s; and the individual biographies of each activist. Narrators in this collection include Kazembe Balagun, Jesse Ehrensaft-Hawley, Kamau Franklin, Camillo Gaston-Greenberg, Orlando Green, Neha Guatam, Chris Gunderson, Sabrine Hammad, Rachel LaForest, Mariano Munoz, Lenina Nadal, Irene Neofotistos, Brad Sigal, suzy subways, and Hank Williams.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by interviewee's first name, in the order in which it was received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Dr. Amaka Okechukwu in October 2021; the accession number associated with this gift is 2021.055.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Biographical Note
SLAM! was a citywide radical student activist group, based at Hunter College (City University of New York) and formed in 1996 out of the dissolution of the CUNY Coalition in 1995. SLAM!'s main organizing concern was to stop the budget cuts and tuition increases at CUNY. The group also organized around welfare, Ethnic Studies, police on campus, incarceration, war, and other social justice movements.
Between 2012-2014, Dr. Amaka Okechukwu, interdisciplinary scholar, author, oral historian, and Assistant Professor in the Department of Sociology and Anthropology at George Mason University, conducted interviews with activists who were members of SLAM! These oral histories were recorded as a part of Dr. Okechukwu's dissertation research which she completed in the Department of Sociology at NYU.
Student movements -- New York (N.Y.); College students -- Political activity -- New York (N.Y.); Discrimination in higher education -- New York (N.Y.); Universities and Colleges -- Open admission -- New York (N.Y.); Student-administrator relationships; Oral histories (literary works); City University of New York; Subways, Suzy; Okechukwu, Amaka
- Brad Sigal, 2012-2014; cuid34936 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_1)
- Camillo Gaston-Greenberg, 2012-2014; cuid34937 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_2)
- Chris Gunderson, 2012-2014; cuid34938 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_3)
- Hank Williams, 2012-2014; cuid34939 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_4)
- Irene Neofotistos, 2012-2014; cuid34940 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_5)
- Jesse Ehrensaft-Hawley, 2012-2014; cuid34941 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_6)
- Kamau Franklin, 2012-2014; cuid34942 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_7)
- Kazembe Balagun, 2012-2014; cuid34943 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_8)
- Lenina Nadal, 2012-2014; cuid34944 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_9)
- Mariano Munoz, 2012-2014; cuid34945 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_10)
- Neha Guatam, 2012-2014; cuid34946 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_11)
- Orlando Green, 2012-2014; cuid34947 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_12)
- Rachel LaForest, 2012-2014; cuid34948 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_13)
- Sabrine Hammad, 2012-2014; cuid34949 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_14)
- suzy subways, 2012-2014; cuid34950 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_799_ER_15)